#### 710 Bellevue, Gladstone Oregon 97027

(503) 344-4727 workerbee33@live.com

## \*BILL EDWARDS \*

### **OBJECTIVE**

To obtain a rewarding position with a great company, where I can utilize previous experience in processing, operations, and customer service to raise the bar for company standards

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

# STATE FARM INSURANCE, PORTLAND, OR 2/2012 - CURRENT RESERVE INSURANCE AGENT

Working part-time as a self employed, contracted self start up Insurance and Financial Securities Agent. Marketing self and insurance product line and financial securities and investments, Marketing and selling via, business to business, cold calling, internet, via miscellaneous business and commerce groups, meetings, and networking.

#### CONTRACT TEMP , PORTLAND METRO AREA, OR 5/2009 -1/2012 TEMPORARY EMPLOYEE

Worked as contract temporary employee with Wells Fargo, Bank Of America, and TVG. I worked as a Loan Processor, a Printing Engineer, and a Call Center Representative, I opened new accounts, handled tech support calls, handled wire transfers, worked with Bank of America during its transition to a complete paperless mortgage system.

#### CITYWIDE MORTGAGE, ALISO VIEJO, CA 5/2006 - 3/2008 PRODUCTION MANAGER

In charge of tracking and analyzing and reporting progress of all loan officers and telemarketers; reassigned loans over a month old with no movement; Processed all of the difficult to approve loans. Provided daily, weekly, and month end reports. Analyzed profit, performance, and statistics.

#### GREAT AMERICAN LENDING, NEWPORT BEACH, CA 9/2004 - 4/2006 LOAN OFFICER

Worked in Sales originating new clients selling 1st and 2nd mortgage loans, qualifying applicants to put them on the right loan product, from prime to sub-prime applicants, analyzed applicant's financial background, credit, assets, debt to income, Kept track of new loans through to funding.

#### CITY HOME LOAN LLC, IRVINE, CA 5/2003 - 4/2004 LOAN OFFICER

Cold called potential borrowers, sold wholesale brokered mortgage loans 1st and 2nds. I processed all of my own loans from submission to funding. Analyzed documentation, credit, applicant's financial background, assets, interest rates, and various lender loan products.

#### **EDUCATION**

CLACKAMAS COMMUNITY
COLLEGE OREGON CITY, OR
1/09 - 12/09
Business Major

GLOBAL TESOL COLLEGE LOS ANGELES, CA 2007 Certified to teach English as a second language

01/02 - 08/02
Pneumatic Hydro Mechanical and Electrical Engineering US Navy Certified Engineer

**UNITED SATES NAVY** 

#### LANGUAGES

Conversational Japanese Intermediate Spanish

#### **SUMMARY**

Customer service oriented professional with 10 years experience interacting with the public. Highly qualified in service-based, processing and finance positions, requiring an emphasis on communication, deadlines, and customer satisfaction in a fast-paced environment. Strong team player. A proven and verifiable record for utilizing strong technical and interpersonal skills to enhance organizational efficiency and profitability. Committed to quality performance, gaining company profit, with an ability to learn new procedures quickly.

#### REFERENCES

Business Associate – Steve Lersvidhaya (714) 323-9068 Business Associate Davis Nicart (714) 330-3318 Personal friend Robert Herman (562) 756-3716

RAISING THE BAR IN COMPANY STANDARDS.